Lisa Leghorn Papers, 1966-1982
Sophia Smith Collection
Lisa Leghorn Papers
1966-1982
Leghorn, Lisa
MS 270 UUID:d7351b56-2a66-4802-b255-a6d929762a3c
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Author, Feminist. The Lisa Leghorn Papers consist of her research files, organized by subject. Types of material include articles, notes, correspondence, published and unpublished writings, and printed material. The files relate to her books on women and development; woman and hunger; women, economics and housework. There are also materials on battered women (including Laura X case); women's rights in Africa, Latin America, Asia, the Caribbean and the U.S.; and the International Women's Year Conference in Houston in 1977.
Biographical Note
Feminist and author Lisa Leghorn received her Master's degree from Goddard College. She is the author of Social Responses to Battered Women (1976), co-author of Who really starves?: Women and World Hunger (Lisa Leghorn and Mary Roodkowsky, 1977); Woman's Worth: Sexual Economics and the World of Women (Lisa Leghorn and Katherine Parker, 1981); and co-author (with Betsy Warrior) of Houseworker's Handbook (1974), as well as numerous published articles. In the 1970's Leghorn worked with Transition House, a battered women's shelter in Boston.
No further biographical information is available at this time.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lisa Leghorn Papers consist of her research files, organized by subject. Types of material include articles, notes, correspondence, published and unpublished writings, and printed material. The files relate to her books on women and development; woman and hunger; women, economics and housework. There are also materials on battered women (including Laura X case); women's rights in Africa, Latin America, Asia, the Caribbean and the U.S.; and the International Women's Year Conference in Houston in 1977.
The Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Lisa Leghorn donated her Papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1987. Periodic additions to this collection are expected and may not be included in this record.
Leghorn, Lisa; Feminists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources; Food supply -- Developing countries; Hunger -- History -- 20th century -- Sources; National Women's Conference (1st: 1977: Houston, Tex.); Women -- Economic conditions; Women in development -- International cooperation -- History -- Sources; Women -- International cooperation -- History -- Sources; Women -- Nutrition -- Social aspects; Women -- Social conditions.; Women's rights -- United States -- History -- 20th century - Sources
- "Baby Bottle": periodical, resources list and clippings1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Battered women
  - Miscellaneous periodicals1977-1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Leghorn's "Social Responses to Battered Women"1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Early feminist movement
  - Published material: clippings, periodicals, and mailings1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Writing1966-1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Housework
  - Clippings, papers, pamphlets and periodicals1973-1980 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Writing1973-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- International Women's Year Conference (Houston): mailings and printed material1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Women and development: official reports, clippings, pamphlets and a paper1975-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Women and economics, paid work and financial independence: clippings and articles1975-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Women and global culture
  - Cross-culturally and internationally: clippings and articles1974-1981 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Egalitarian societies: papers, clippings and booklets1975-1977, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Africa: clippings, papers, booklets, periodicals1975-1976, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Asia: mailings, clippings, periodicals1973-1980, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Women in the Carribean, China and Cuba: printed material, mailings1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Women in Latin America: publications1975-1978, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Women and hunger
  - Paper, periodicals1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Women in a Hungry World" packet1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Periodicals (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Women: A Journal of Liberation (vol.3, no.4)n.d. (Box 3)
  - No More Fun and Games / The Female State: A Journal of Female Liberation (issues 2-5)1969-1971 (Box 3)